So numbers in Python, these are all integers, and we can always verify that by calling
type, there are also floats in Python, so numbers that have decimal points.
Something that's a little tricky that might bite you, this is a valid float.
You don't need to have a decimal point after.
You shouldn't really define your floats like this, it's confusing, but if you see this
in Python code, just know that that's not a syntax error.
And then there are also complex numbers, and these end with the character j.
I'm not a math person, I don't think I've ever used complex numbers in my Python code,
but they're there if you need them.
Like you saw earlier, these types are just objects under the hood, you can also declare
them by calling the constructor for that built-in type, so I can say into five.
I can also pass in a string in here, same thing for float.
If I pass in, let's say an integer into the float constructor, we'll return a float back.
Generally, you never want to do this in your code unless you are converting between
types, but this is something that you might see.
One example of converting between types is if you're using an old-style string formatting,
if you try to, for example, concatenate, we'll talk about strings a little bit later, a string
with a number, you're going to get a type error that says you can only concatenate strings
and not ins, so in this case, you can pass in the number five to the stir method.
Again, with modern Python string formatting, you won't really ever need to do this, but
could happen.
You can do all the standard mathematical operations that you might expect with Python
numbers, you can add them up and you can multiply them.
You can divide them, note that if you divide two integers, the type that you get back
is going to be a float.
If you want to do integer division, you need to use two slashes, and that will get you
an integer back.
You can also raise to the powers, so let's say we have X equals four and Y equals three,
you can say X to the power of three or X to the power of Y.
So everything that you might expect, and then you can also use parentheses to make sure
that things happen in the order that you want, and that is all a valid Python code.
Python has a few more built-in methods that are useful for numbers, and you might hear
me say built-in methods, what does that mean?
You saw earlier in our tour of a Python program that I had to import the request module.
Later on, we'll see how to import modules from the standard library.
When I'm using these built-ins, I don't need to import anything.
They're just available in Python.
And the three helpful methods for math are min and max or rounds.
So for min, you could pass in some values, and it will always return the smallest of them.
The same is true for max, except the opposite.
This will return 10,000, because it is the largest number in that list.
You can also use round to round down decimals, or round them up.
There are built-in blend types in Python, just like we saw that none is a keyword.
In Python, the blend types are defined with uppercase true, and lowercase false.
These are keywords.
Something of note in Python that I've seen tripped people up, again, in Python, everything
is an object.
These booleans are objects, and, in fact, under the hood, they are subclasses of integers.
That means that under the hood, true has a value of 1, and false has a value of 0.
Don't do this, please.
Because of that, you can actually add these together or do anything that you could do to numbers.
Don't do this, but Python, in fact.